Chrysalis ChangeLog

What is Chrysalis? Chrysalis is a code library written in C# Microsoft's .NET v4.2.1 Framework.
The function of Chrysalis is very simple: Encode a file or a folder into a .PNG image. Chrysalis 
can also decode the image back into a file or folder. The type of data encoded (File / Folder) is stored in the
.PNG image itself, so no specification is needed when decoding the file. 

So how does it work? Well that is a very complex question and therefore, requires a complex answer. I will explain
exactly how it works in great detail, although I warn you, there is quite a bit of computer terms including the idea of
ARGB color, how a Bitmap object works, what a Byte is, how files are read, what a .ZIP file is, and what a .GZ file is.

So, I shall now define all of the terms above to make the explination a tad bit more understandable. If you are familiar will
all of the above terms feel free to skip this section. Alright, let's begin.

ARGB Color: Color on a computer is normally represented in RGB form. RGB stands for Red, Green, and Blue. RGB notation takes three
numbers, 0-255, for each color component. So if you wanted to represent just red, the notation would be RGB(255, 0, 0), showing that
100% of the color is red because there are no other color parts other than red, furthermore, the brightness of said red component is
at the highest it can be, ergo, RGB(20, 0, 0) would show a dull red where RGB(255, 0, 0) would show the most vivid red. Furthermore,
RGB(0, 0, 0) would be black, and RGB(255, 255, 255) would be white. You can also mix the components. If you wanted a hot-pink, that could
be RGB(255, 0, 150) because Red and Blue make purple, and hot-pink is simply a more-red-intensive purple. Now you may have been wondering
"Alright, I understand this whole RGB thing, but what the heck is the 'A'?" Well the A stands for Alpha. If you have ever dabbled in Photoshop,
you may have noticed that an image (which is just a collection of pixels will individual colors respectfuly) can be made transparent. The alpha 
is also a value from 0 to 255 however 0 is 100% invisable and 255 is 0% invisable. So with RGB, you can have 256^3 possibilities, however ARGB has
256^4 possibilites. Therefore, |𝛥v| = 4,278,190,080 where v1 = 256^3 and v2 = 256^4. This means that there are over 4 billion more values that 
ARGB could have. Thusly, we use ARGB in this project.

Bitmap Objects: In the world of coding, files / data can exists in three locations: Hard Drive, Managed Memory, and Unmanaged Memory.
We use a concept known as Marshaling to transfer data from Unmanaged Memory to and from Managed Memory. The good news is although there a 
buttload of Marshaling that takes place when using the Bitmap object, it is all automatic for what we want to do in this project. So forget that 
Managed and Unmanaged Memory are different, I shall only refer to Memory as simply "Mem". Now a computer uses Mem to read and write files VERY 
quickly. The amount of mem a computer has is represented by how much RAM it has. RAM stands for Random Access Memory, so when you boot up a computer,
code for "How to open a file" is loaded into Mem, that way every time you click or drag a window or open an app, the computer has that code on hand,
and doesn't have to go hunting for that code in the hard drive. As an app developer, we must be very aware of how much Mem we use. When declaring a
variable, we load that data into Mem. Now a number will be very small. Just a couple bytes of Mem, and most modern computers have 8-32 GB of Mem.
However, when we load an image into RAM, we must understand that the size on the disk will not be the size in Mem. In the hard drive, it has a
compression. .PNG is a type of way to store the vast amount of values in a space-effective way. There is no compression in RAM, this is known as the 
'RAW' form of data. 'RAW' data is crazy big, this means we can quicky use up GBs worth of Mem if we are using Chrysalis to encode a file or folder larger
than say, a half a GB in compressed form. Now on to Bitmaps as an object. Bitmaps are very complex, but we will only be using a couple features of them.
At the core of a Bitmap, you can think of it as a Matrix of 'Color' Objects. A Color object has an A, R, G, and B value that we can access. So taking a
trip down memory lane, lets review what a matrix is. A matrix is an array of arrays. [ Value one, Value Two, Value Three ] is an array, but 
[ [Value 0-0, Value 0-1, Value 0-2],
  [Value 1-0, Value 1-1, Value 1-2],
  [Value 2-0, Value 2-1, Value 2-2] ] is a matrix.
Or in math class, you may have seen it as:
┌	 			  ┐
│ Value 0-0  Value 0-1  Value 0-2 │
│    				  │
│ Value 1-0  Value 1-1  Value 1-2 │
│ 				  │
│ Value 0-2  Value 2-1  Value 2-2 │
└				  ┘
However insted of 'Value X-Y', we would have a matrix of color ARGB objects. The bitmap object also has two Methods that I used. GetPixal(x, y)
and SetPixal(x, y, Color). They do exactly what they sound like. If we defined a bitmap object that had a 4x4 grid of pixals for a total of 16 
indiviual pixals (4^2), as 'B' `Bitmap B = new Bitmap(4, 4);`, it would look like this:
    ┌        							             ┐
    │ ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0) │
    │ 								             │
    │ 								             │
    │ ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0) │
B = │ 								             │
    │ 								             │
    │ ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0) │
    │ 								             │
    │ 								             │
    │ ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0) │
    └								             ┘
So then to set the pixal at (2, 3) to a bright, opaque red, we can just say `B.SetPixal(2, 3, Color.FromArgb(255, 255, 0, 0));`
The Result would be:
    ┌        							                 ┐
    │ ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)     │
    │ 								                 │
    │ 								                 │
    │ ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)     │
B = │ 								                 │
    │ 								                 │
    │ ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(255, 255, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0) │
    │  								                 │
    │ 								                 │
    │ ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)  ARGB(0, 0, 0, 0)     │
    └								                 ┘
We can get a specific value of a specific location of the image as well. For example, `B.GetPixal(2, 3).A;` would evaluate to 255.
Now, once we have this image how we want it in Mem, we need to take it out of mem, and put it into the hard disk. To do this, we use the
`Save(path, ImageEncoding);` Method. The path is where we want to save the image to. So say we wanted to save the image as 'my image.png' 
to the desktop. We can do this `B.Save(Enviornment.GetFolderPath(Enviornment.SpecialFolder.Desktop) + "/my image.png", ImageEncoding.PNG);`
Now once we have saved the image to the hard disk, we need to re-allocate the Mem so that other things can use it. Right now, the image is copied
to the desktop, but still exists in Mem. To fully delete it, we must do two things. The first is to mark it so that the collector knows to remove
the data, and the other is to actually run the Collector. Now an item will always take up as much space as it ever once needed at its max. So in other
words, if ValueOne took up 5 Bytes of Mem, and then took up 18 Bytes, but then went back down to 10 Bytes, we would still have 18 Bytes allocated to ValueOne.
When the Garbage Collector is run, it looks for any spots where a value is allocated Mem, but not taking up any bytes, and then sets the allocated bytes
to zero, thereby destroing the object, and freeing the Mem to be used for something else. So step one is to make the amount of bytes that our image, B,
is taking up equal to 0, no Bytes. To do this, there is a special keyword, `null`. So we say 'B = null; GC.Collect();` This sets the bytes the image
is using to 0, and then runs the garbage collector to free that Mem. Geez, that was very long and probably way more complicated than needed. Just know that
a Bitmap Object is a matrix of colors. Cool?

Bytes: A Byte is one of the most complex and low-level advanced concepts in my opinion in c# or any programming language. I shall give a breif overview.
A Byte is a collection of Bits. 8 Bits to a Byte for what we will be using. A bit is either 0 or 1. So if you looked at the bits of a byte, it would look
like 10110010. This is the 'cody stuff' that Hollywood portrays computer programming and hacking to involve, although if you didnt already know this,
it is very rare that you will ever have to manualy see, provide, or manipulate data on a Bit by Bit level without using a BitWise operator such as XOR, <<=,
=>>, <<, or >>. If you would like to learn more about Bits and Bitwise operators, go to the MSDN forums and search for "C# Bitwise" and grow your metal library of
wisdom. I would love to explain it in psudo-plain english here without all the jargon, but the truth is I don't really understand it myself. However what I
do know is what will be implimented. You can think of a byte as a numeric representation of a value. A byte is simply a number that is equal to the order
of bits it contains and thereby, can be equal to many many different values. For example, the letter 'A' is equal to 065. So just think of a byte as a 
special type of number that is just a representation of any type of data.

Loading Files: This will be a short one, I promise. When loading a file, we take an array of bytes from that file starting at an index and load it into Mem.
`byte[] data = File.ReadAllBytes(path);`

.ZIP / .GZ Files: All you need to know is that .zip is a compressed FOLDER. It is a collection of files that are compressed into one folder. .GZ is a single
compressed file. To compress a folder using GZ, we first need to create a single file archive. Common files for this is known as a .TAR file, as it is 
supported by Linux, MacOS, and Windows (using 7zip). I chose to use .ZIP.GZ over .TAR.GZ because this program is strictly windows-based as of when I am
writing this, although I may port it to Mono and run a linux version, let's stick with windows right now.

Alright, that was the end of the definitions and concepts. By now you should be semi-versed in the world of data manipulation and image creation, with 
your new knolage, let the fun begin!.

Okay, so the first thing I did was I wrote a function to get an ARGB value from the value of a Byte. The algorithm is actually dead simple, it goes like this.

First, we need to define a variable to hold the byte value to encode, lets use 'val'.
We need a MAX constant, a number that each value (there are 4, A, R, G, and B) can be, so MAX = 255
Cool, next we want to say that A + R + G + B = val. There is more though, I want A to be filled before we start touching R, and A and B to be filled 
before we start touching G, and so on. Now where are many many ways to do this, but the way I chose was by using something known as a conditional return expression.
It looks like this: `var value = (condition) ? true : false;`. So the whole expression evaluates to one of two items based on if the condition is true or false.
The reason I didn't include it in the terms you need to know is beacause although I used it, it is just a very compact way to write many if statments. If
statments are much easier, it is just `if (condition) { }` where the code in the brackets run if the condition is true. So we just ask first off, is val 
less than MAX (255)? if it is, well then we are done! just return ARGB(val, 0, 0, 0) because the A slot can hold the full value of val. Now lets say that 
val is larger than MAX. That's okay, we just need to fill the first slot with 255 and move to the next slot. We need to determine if val can fit into two
slots, to do this, we can simply subtract MAX from val because we used MAX in the first slot and we are looking for the sum. If val - MAX is less than or equal to
MAX, then we are done as well, just return ARGB(MAX, val - MAX, 0, 0). This pattern repeats for if val - (2 * MAX) then return 
ARGB(MAX, MAX, val - (2 * MAX), 0), or lastly, if none of the above are true, then simply return ARGB(MAX, MAX, MAX, val - (3 * MAX)). In fancy math 
notation, this can be represented as:

ƒ(x) = 